A Guide to the Thomas Simmons Music Collection 1940-1966
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Thomas Simmons Music Collection 1940-1966
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
4824-f
This collection consists of ca. 100 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was given to the library by David Baker of Hartford, Connecticut on March 16, 1988.
Biographical/Historical Information
American composer.
Scope and Content Information
The collection contains musical settings by Simmons for traditional ballads collected by Winston Wilkinson, as well as for troubadour songs and miscellaneous lyrics. Of interest are a musical play "The wife of Usher's well" in collaboration with Frank Baer, John Powell's introduction to Wilkinson's Blue Ridge ballads, and Cecil Sharp's arrangement of "Fanny Blair".
Correspondents include Frank Baer, Elio Gianturco, Sarah Cecil Stafford, and Winston Wilkinson.
Contents List
- "The Ballad of Sharon McTarish" n.d.
- "Blue Ridge Ballads" 1948-1956, n.d.
- "The Caterpillar who became a Butterfly" n.d.
- "The Channerin Worm" n.d.
- "The End" n.d.
- "The Linden Tree" 1950
- "Madeline" n.d.
- "Sonatine" 1963
- "Troubador Song" 1960-1962
- "The Wife of Usher's Well" 1961-1966
- Miscellaneous Music Scores n.d.